(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-31T21:14:16.998063",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
welcome to , we come to welcome to my house
Welcome to, welcome to, welcome to my house!
welcome to , welcome to welcome to my heart
Welcome to, welcome to, welcome to my heart!
umare tate no asahi ga sansan
The newborn morning sun shines bright,
mizutamari ga hi katte kirakira
Puddles sparkle in the light,
kyou mo osouji pika pika
Cleaning up sparkling clean again today,
neko no te mo kari tai kurai nyo
I'm so busy I could use all the help I can get!
tsumaranai koto ki ni shinai nyo
Don't sweat the small stuff,
misu chatte mo koron jatte mo maemuki ni go go !
Even if you slip or fall, keep a positive spirit!
kyou mo atashi wa tai isogashi
I'm super busy again today,
tsukarechattemo sentou moodo nyo
Even if I'm tired, I'm going into battle mode!
welcome to , welcome to welcome to my house
Welcome to, welcome to, welcome to my house!
welcome to , welcome to welcome to my heart
Welcome to, welcome to, welcome to my heart!
kyou mo kimi ga kite kureru no matteru nyo
I'm waiting for you to come see me today!
shizundeku yuuhi wa kirakira
The setting sun sways gently,
maigo no koneko wa fuwa fuwa
The lost kitten is fluffy and soft,
kyou mo ashiato furafura
My feet are stumbling around again today,
ohisama mo gokurousama da nyo
Good work to the sun as well!
sugi chatta koto furi kaeranai nyo
Don't look back on things that have passed,
shippai shi chatte mo hazukashi kutte mo koukai wa no ! no !
Even if you fail or feel embarrassed, no regrets!
itsumo atashi wa tsi isogashi
I'm always super busy,
ochikomanai de sentou moodo nyo
Don't get down, switch to battle mode!
welcome to , welcome to welcome to my house
Welcome to, welcome to, welcome to my house!
welcome to , welcome to welcome to my heart
Welcome to, welcome to, welcome to my heart!
kyou mo kimi ga kite kureru no matteru nyo
I'm waiting for you to come visit me today!
ashioto patapata osouji pika pika
Pitter-patter footsteps, sparkling cleaning,
yuuhi wa yura yura koneko wa fuwa fuwa
The setting sun sways, the cat is fluffy,
tsumarani koto ki ni shinai yo
Don't worry about boring things,
misu chatte mo koron jatte mo
Even if you make a mistake or trip,
sugi chatta koto furi kaeranai nyo
Don't look back on the past,
shippai shi chatte mo hazukashi kutte mo
Even if you fail or feel embarrassed,
ochikomanai de sentou moodo nyo
Don't get down, switch to battle mode!
welcome to , welcome to welcome to my house
Welcome to, welcome to, welcome to my house!
welcome to , welcome to welcome to my heart
Welcome to, welcome to, welcome to my heart!
kyou mo kimi ga kite kureru no matteru nyo
I'm waiting for you to come visit me today!
matteru nyo
I'm waiting for you!
初めましての方も、初めまして。
To those of you meeting me for the first time,
私、ホロライブ3期生、不知火フレアと申します。
I am Shiranui Flare, 3rd generation of Hololive.
Overdose is Brothers & Hello! My name is Flare Shiranui!
1曲目でこんなヘロヘロで大丈夫か
Will I be okay being this exhausted on the first song?
今日はですね、私誕生日、え、生誕祭ライブにお集まりいただきまして本当に本当にありがとうございます。
Today, thank you all so much for gathering for my birthday live.
なんか最初からね、あの、待合所でもすでにねなんかスーパーチャットとかたくさん投げていただいて、本当に本当にありがとうございます。
Right from the start, in the waiting room, you guys were already sending lots of Super Chats... Thank you so much, really!
今回ですね、たくさん、あの、楽曲とかもね用意して、みんなに楽しんでいただく準備はできておりますので
This time, we've prepared lots of songs, and we're ready for you all to enjoy it,
最後まで楽しんでいただけたら嬉しいです。
so I'd be happy if you could enjoy it all the way to the end.
でですね、こちら……え、ごめん、ちょっと使い切っちゃった。
And, um, here... Ah, sorry, I used it all up.
えっと、こちらですね、えー見えること？ こちらハッシュタグありますので、じゃあよかったらTwitterでいっぱいツイートしてくれたら嬉しいです。
Um, here, um, can you see this? There's a hashtag for this, so I'd be happy if you tweet a lot on Twitter.
目指せ！トレンド1位！私をトレンド1位に連れてって！
Aim for #1 trending! Take me to #1 on trending!
なんか、動画が届いてるらしいんだ。なんかサプライズ動画らしいんだけど、ちょっと見てみよっか。誰？
Apparently, a video has arrived. It seems to be a surprise video, so let's take a look. Who is it?
お前かよ！ ノエルちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！ハニーストラップの周防パトラです。
It's you! Noel-chan, happy birthday! This is Suou Patra from Honey Strap.
今日はね、フレアちゃんに誕生日プレゼントを持ってきました～！
Today, I brought a birthday present for Flare-chan~!
マジか、イェーイ！
Seriously? Yay!
フレアちゃんに歌ってほしい曲があって、オケを作ったから、あの、ぜひぜひ歌ってほしいなぁなんて思ってます！
There's a song I wanted Flare-chan to sing, and I made the instrumental, so I really hope you'll sing it!
みんな～、フレアちゃんの歌を聴け～！
Everyone~, listen to Flare-chan's song~!
ではでは！ ノエルちゃんと……ありがとう！末永く、お幸せにね！
Well then! With Noel-chan... Thank you! May you be happy together forever!
周防パトラでした～！ あ、バイバ～イ！ あ、抱き枕、抱いて？ うるせぇな！
This was Suou Patra~! Ah, bye-bye! Ah, hug the dakimakura? Shut up!
ノエルちゃんパトラありがとうって言うね、あの、まぁ前フリをしたところなんですけど
Saying 'Noel-chan, Patra, thank you'—well, I just set that up,
今回の楽曲に関しまして、あの、ちょっとね、パトラにね、あの、色々スケジュールとか忙しい合間を縫って貰って、あの、まぁフレアちゃん誕生日だからねって言ってね、ちょっとあの、楽曲を何曲か、あの、作ってくれたんですよ。
regarding this song, um, Patra squeezed it into her busy schedule, and said 'Since it's Flare-chan's birthday,' and made several songs for me.
はい、なので、あの、まぁどれがねパトラが作ったかとか、まぁそういうお話はちょっとまた後日お話しさせていただけたらなって思うんですけど
So, um, which ones Patra made and such, I thought I'd talk about that another day, but
ちょっとね、なんか最後の抱き枕に関しちゃちょっと、言い訳えーな、うるせぇなっつって(笑)
about that last dakimakura, I was like, 'Save the excuses, shut up!' (laughs)
いつもありがとね、パトラ。そしてお誕生日プレゼントってことで素敵な曲をいただきましたので
Thank you as always, Patra. And since I received such a wonderful song as a birthday present,
早速ですけどね、ちょっと1曲、まこれはねあのパトラが制作してくれた曲なんで、ぜひぜひちょっと聞いていただきたいなっていう、はい。
we'll start right away with the first song—well, this is a song Patra produced, so I definitely want you all to listen to it.
曲、私がずっと、あの、歌いたいんだよなって思ってたんですけど、オケがなかったので歌えなかった曲なので、ちょっと早速、ちょっと2曲目、いきたいなと思います！はい、では、えー、それでは聞いてください。「絶望と希望」
It's a song I've always wanted to sing, but since there was no instrumental, I couldn't, so I'd like to go straight into the second song! Well then, please listen to it. 'Despair and Hope'.
悲しみ痛みは always 誰にも言えなくてそっと
Sadness and pain are always unable to be told to anyone, softly
電話のあとにこぼれ落ちる marbles どうせひとりぼっちなんて
After the phone call, falling marbles, thinking I'm all alone
バカだな 幾星霜 人は心に
How foolish, over countless years, people in their hearts
逃げ道を作ってる
create an escape route
知らないうちに弱さ握りしめて
unwittingly clutching their weakness tightly
悲しみ、痛みは always
Sadness and pain are always
そっと電話の後に零れ落ちていく my tears
softly spilling down after the phone call, my tears
どうせ一人ぼっちなんてバカな泣き虫
A foolish crybaby who is alone anyway
人は心に逃げ道をつくってる
People make escape routes in their hearts
知らないうちに弱さにぎりしめてるよ
Clinging to weakness without knowing it
人ごみに埋め尽くされた 街の上に孤独な空がある
Above the crowd-filled town, there is a lonely sky
いつもきっと大地を見ては 私を探していた
Always looking at the earth, searching for myself
今日という波が砂浜に 打ち寄せてしぶきを上げる時この涙が海に落ちるよ
When today's wave hits the sandy beach and splashes, these tears fall into the ocean
ひろい集めたいいつかの夢の破片 届いて my dream
Wanna collect pieces of some dream, reach my dream
強がるだけの every days
Every days of just acting tough
大人になれないもどかしさが続いていく
The frustration of not being able to grow up continues
長い夜は so lonely 誰かに慰めてもらってもなぜか虚しい
Long nights are so lonely, even if someone comforts me, somehow it feels empty
部屋の隅には懐かしいオルゴールの音
In the corner of the room, the nostalgic sound of a music box
静かな歌が心しみつけてくるよ
A quiet song seeps into my heart
過去と今とが重なり 駆け抜けていく心の交差点
Past and present overlap, running through the intersection of the heart
壊れそうなガラスの扉今この手で開こう
Let's open this fragile glass door with these hands now
絶望と希望の間には 何が立ち尽くしているの?
What is standing between despair and hope?
目をつむって思い浮かべる 心中散らばる夢の破片
Closing eyes and imagining, scattered pieces of dreams in the heart
あなたにもあるよ 世界中で一番ちっぽけな生き物だろう
You have it too, probably the tiniest creature in the world
人は押し流されて生きていくよ たった一つの勇気があれば
People are swept along as they live, if they have just one courage
よかったそれだけでこんなに 傷つくことを逃げ出さないで この道歩けたのに...
Good thing, just for that, without running away from getting hurt, I was able to walk this path...
これから巡っていく季節と無情な闇風の中で 誰かを愛し誰のために 戦っていくんだね
In the seasons and merciless dark winds that will revolve from now on, loving someone and fighting for someone
きっと最後まで走りつづける 強さはその答えなんだろう
Surely, running all the way to the end, that strength must be the answer
負けないように忘れないように もう一度瞳は空を見上げるから
So as not to lose, so as not to forget, once more my eyes look up at the sky
ただ一つの勇気があればよかった
If I had just one bit of courage, it would have been enough.
それだけでこんなに 傷つくことを
Just with that, getting hurt so much...
逃げ出さないで この道歩けたのに
Without running away, I was able to walk this path...
これから巡っていく季節と無情な 闇風の中で
In the seasons and merciless dark winds revolving from now on
誰かを愛し誰のために 戦っていくんだね
Loving someone and fighting for someone...
きっと最後まで走り続ける 強さはその答えなんだろう 負けないように忘れないように
Surely, running all the way to the end, that strength must be the answer, so as not to lose, so as not to forget
もう一度瞳は空を見上げるから
Once more my eyes look up at the sky
はーい！お聴きいただきました曲は、川島あいさんの「絶望と希望」っていう曲でした。
Hi there! The song you just heard was Kawashima Ai's "Zetsubou to Kibou."
私の大好きなアーティストさんの曲なんですけど、前々からちょっと歌いたいなと思っていたので本当に本当にパトラありがとうね！
It's a song by my favorite artist, and I've been wanting to sing it for a long time, so Patra, thank you so much!
ちょっとお水飲んでいいですか？
Can I drink some water?
あ、ありがとうございます。
Ah, thank you very much.
あ、運営さんがめちゃくちゃ親切。
Ah, management is super kind.
はぁ、美味しい。お水が美味しい。
Haah, delicious. The water is delicious.
ありがとう！あ、そういえばね、ちょっとツッコミ忘れてたんですけど、ここにな、ちょっとあの、今までいなかったの、金の妻がいるんですお。
Thank you! Ah, by the way, I forgot to mention, there's a golden wife here who wasn't here before.
でもね、ちょっと次の曲はですね、あの、ちょっと今回最初で最後の、あの...
But, you know, the next song is... well, this time, first and last...
コラボ曲というか、ちょっとゲストとして呼んでいるのですけど
A collaboration song, or rather, I invited her as a guest,
ちょっと邪魔なのでちょっとはけていただこうかと
and since she's in the way, I'll have her step aside.
はい、アルパンダちゃ、待って今の
Right, Alpanda-cha—wait, what was that?
ちょっとこいつちょっと一旦はけてもらって
Hey, could you just have this guy step aside for a moment?
でですね、皆さん、今ね楽しんでいただけてると思いますけれども、地獄が始まります
And then, everyone, I'm sure you're enjoying yourselves, but hell is about to begin.
ちょっと今から地獄が始まりますよ。何の曲ですか?ちょっと聞かせていただきたいと思いますけれども。
Hell is about to begin right now. What song is it? I'd like to let you hear it, but...
ではですね、曲のタイトル言っちゃいたいと思いますよ。えー、チューリングラブ。
Well then, I'd like to tell you the song title. Um... Turing Love.
あー、恋の定義がわかんない
Ah, I don't know the definition of love.
まずスキって基準もわかんない
I don't even know what qualifies as liking someone.
要は、恋してるときが恋しい
Basically, I miss being in love.
客観? 主観? エビデンスプリーズ!
Objective? Subjective? Evidence, please!
愛は計算じゃ解けない
Love can't be solved by calculation.
まず普通の計算も解けない
In fact, I can't even do ordinary math.
要は、そんな状態が愛らしい
Basically, that state of being is adorable.
もう大大部分の事象において Q があって A を出して解けるのに
In almost all situations, there's a Q and you find the A to solve it,
勘違いして間違って解いのないこの気持ちはなんだろう
mistaken, getting it wrong, what is this unanswerable feeling?
検証ススメヨ
Let's verify!
モーションは相対性にステイ
Motions stay relative.
チューリングラブ 見つめあったって解けないメロディ
Turing Love, a melody that can't be solved just by gazing
ワットイズラブ いま 123 で証そうか
What is Love? Shall we prove it now with 1, 2, 3?
言葉で生み出すクエスチョン (クエスチョン!)
A question born of words (Question!)
ハートで高鳴るアンサー (アンサー!)
An answer beating in the heart (Answer!)
測ったって不確実性 ぼくらの BPM
Even if measured, the uncertainty is our BPM.
チューリングラブ 宙に舞ったって信じないけど
Turing Love, even if floating in space, I won't believe it,
フォーリングラブ 今は ABC すらバグりそうだ
Falling Love, right now even ABC seems like it's going to bug out.
なんでか教えてオイラー (オイラー!)
Tell me why, Euler (Euler!)
感想聞かせてフェルマー (フェルマー!)
Let me hear your thoughts, Fermat (Fermat!)
予測不可能性 今触れてみる
Let's touch upon unpredictability now.
さあ証明しよう (証明しよう) 間違いのないように
Come on, let's prove it so there's no mistake.
証明しよう (証明しよう) この感情全部全部
Let's prove every single one of these emotions.
証明しよう (証明しよう) 正解があるなら
Let's prove it if there is a correct answer.
証明しよう (証明しよう) シンプルな Q.E.D.
Let's prove it with a simple Q.E.D.
今日こそ証明したい! 目に見えない 難題を ASAP!
Today is the day we want to prove invisible difficult problems, ASAP!
今日こそ証明したい!
Today is the day I want to prove it!
正面に見えない 無理難題を
Facing invisible, impossible problems,
導き出したい たどり着きたい 最適解へ
I want to deduce it, reach the optimal solution.
何度遠回りだってぶつかっちゃったって 不思議なこのアノマリーを解き明かす定性条件です
No matter how many detours or collisions, it's a qualitative condition to solve this mysterious anomaly.
3次元括弧リチャードにおける2点AB間の距離を求めよ
Find the distance between two points A and B in 3D brackets.
敵な感じだと思ってたのに
Even though I thought it was a lovely feeling,
予想もこうしか見えてられないし 座標軸にも載っていないから
Expectations aren't even visible, and it's not even on the coordinate axes,
君と生み出してみせたいじゃん 3次元括弧世界におけるこの気持ちの求め方
So I want to create it with you—how to find this feeling in a 3D world.
どんな街だって街だって不安に呑み込もうぜ
No matter what town, let's swallow our anxiety whole,
遠くなって遠くなって揺れるこの気持ちの針も
Getting distant, getting distant, even the needle of this swaying feeling.
条件ススメヨ
Let's proceed with the conditions!
ステップインモーションは相対性にステイ
Step in motion, stay relative.
チューリングラブ 騒ぎ出す胸の痛くなるほど
Turing Love, enough to make my heart pound and ache.
証明は今も角度を増しているようだ
The proof seems to be increasing its angle even now.
曖昧も除外して最大の仮説を今二人なら実証できそう
Excluding ambiguity, the two of us can demonstrate the biggest hypothesis.
チューリングラブ 見つめあったって気づけないメロディ
Turing Love, a melody you wouldn't notice even if you stared.
ワットイズラブ 今は 123 で明かそうか
What is Love? Shall we reveal it now with 1, 2, 3?
言葉で生み出すクエスチョン ハートで得たカナリアアンサー
Question born of words, canary answer gained with the heart.
測ったって不確実性 ぼくらの BPM
Even if measured, uncertainty is our BPM.
チューリングラブ 宙に舞ったってその因果も
Turing Love, even if floating in space, that causality too,
フォーリングラブ 今は ABC 添えろ若いそう
Falling Love, right now let's pair ABC...
なんか教えてオイラー 確かめさせてピタゴラス
Tell me something, Euler. Let me verify, Pythagoras.
確かめにさせて今 予測不可能性 今触れてみる
Let me verify right now, let's touch upon unpredictability.
さあ証明しよう 間違いのないように
Come on, let's prove it so there's no mistake.
証明しよう この感情全部全部
Let's prove all of these emotions.
証明しよう 正解があるなら
Let's prove it if there is a correct answer.
証明しよう 数値そこを越えて
Let's prove it, going beyond numerical values.
証明しよう 間違いのないように
Let's prove it so there's no mistake.
証明しよう この感情全部全部
Let's prove all of these emotions.
証明しよう 正解があるなら
Let's prove it if there is a correct answer.
証明しよう シンプルな Q.E.D.
Let's prove it with a simple Q.E.D.
今日こそ証明したい! 目に見えない 難題を ASAP!
Today is the day we want to prove invisible difficult problems, ASAP!
シンプルな Q.E.D.
A simple Q.E.D.
ふーね！ひっくーいね！
Fu-ne! So low!
でも出ないだろ？
But you couldn't hit those notes, right?
そう、あの、フレアのところは高いから男性です
Yeah, well, Flare's part is high, so it's a guy's part.
高も低もね、ちょっと歌えないから
Neither the high nor low parts can really be sung.
限界が来たぞ
My limit has been reached!
お水飲んでもいい？
Can I drink some water?
飲む飲む。いっぱい飲んでください。
Drink, drink. Please drink lots of it.
だってさっきフレアが歌ってるとき、だいぶ飲んだから
Because earlier when Flare was singing, I drank a lot.
大丈夫、よーし！
It's fine, alright!
てわけですね、はい。
So, yeah.
今回、あの、やっぱりね、ノエルちゃんをちょっとゲストにお呼びしたいなと思って。
This time, I really wanted to invite Noel-chan as a guest.
ね、誰が地獄やねんな。
Hey, who's in hell?!
確かに、地獄だったけども。
True, it was pretty much hell though.
そう、みんなのコメント見てみようよ。
Yeah, let's check everyone's comments.
「いや、すごいパチパチ」って書いてある。
They're writing, "Wow, clapping clapping!"
ありがとう。
Thank you!
てぇてぇも見たよ。
I saw the teetee ones too.
ありがとうござます。
Thank you very much.
果たして、どこまでが本当なんだろう？このコメント。
I wonder how much of these comments are actually true?
え、何何何？
Huh, what what what?
それ、何だよ？これがほんまのデショよ。
What's that? This is the real deal.
いやでもね、ノエルちゃんと一緒にずっと歌いたかったんだよ。
But you know, I always wanted to sing with Noel-chan.
そうですねよ。
That's right.
でもね、ノエルちゃんが、その、私がね、
But Noel-chan, like, when I...
ノエルちゃんが歌いやすい曲と、私が、あの、ノエルちゃんがちょっと...
songs that are easy for Noel-chan to sing, and me, um, Noel-chan kinda...
おねえの話に入んないよ。
Don't drag my older sister into this!
え、シングルはね、あのフレアだからだっちゃとかやり。
Well, singles are... because it's Flare, so let's do something like that.
ノエルちゃんと一緒にいたい曲が、ちょっと2曲ぐらいあったんだけど、どっちがいい？って聞いたら。
There were about two songs I wanted to sing with Noel-chan, and when I asked which one was better,
ノエルがなぜかこっちを選んだんだよな。
Noel somehow chose this one.
いやだって、さ、てぇてぇじゃん、てぇてぇじゃん！てぇてぇからさ、歌いたいじゃん、歌えなくてもね！
Well because, like, it's teetee, right, it's teetee! Since it's teetee, we wanna sing it, even if we can't!
歌えなくてもね！いやでもその気持ちが私はすごく嬉しかった。
Even if we can't! But I was really happy with that feeling.
そう、頑張って、頑張って練習した。
Yeah, I worked hard and practiced.
そう、ちょっと2回目のやつがさ、なんか高く... 高くってなっちゃって。いやほんと、お邪魔してます。ありがとうございます。
Yeah, and the second time it got high... too high. Seriously, I'm intruding. Thank you.
そうなんですよ。
That's right.
ノエルちゃんありがとうね、来てくれて。
Thanks for coming, Noel-chan.
うん。
Yeah.
でですね、今回はこのNSの衣装っていうのがあの、めったにね、ないと思うので。
And so, this time, since we rarely ever wear this NS outfit,
今日はね、ノエフレで、新撮写真会をちょっとちょっぴりだけ時間取らせてもらおうかなって思って、私の思い出作りに付き合ってよ。
today, with NoeFure, we wanted to take a little bit of time for a new photoshoot, so please keep me company for making memories.
いっぱい撮って、あの、このハッシュタグ
Take lots of pictures, and, like, this hashtag
思い出をね、いっぱいツイートしてくれて嬉しい。
tweet lots of memories, I'd be so happy.
ツイートして？
Tweet it?
レディ？
Ready?
どうするどうする？
What should we do, what should we do?
え、ちょっとあのさ、さっきのリハーサルでさ
Oh, wait, let's do that thing we did in rehearsal earlier.
やったやつちょっとやろうよ。
Let's do it.
いやほんと、お邪魔してます。ありがとうございます。
Seriously, sorry for intruding. Thank you.
そうなんですよ。
That's right.
ノエルちゃんありがとうね、来てくれて。
Thanks for coming, Noel-chan.
うん。
Yeah.
でですね、今回このNSスの衣装っていうのがあの、めったにね、ないと思うので。
And so, this time, since we rarely ever wear this NS outfit,
今日はね、ノエフレで、新撮写真会をちょっとちょっぴりだけ時間取らせてもらおうかなって思って。
today, with NoeFure, we wanted to take a little bit of time for a new photoshoot.
私の思い出作りに付き合ってよ。
Please keep me company for making memories.
いっぱい撮って、あのこのハッシュタグ思い出をね、いっぱいツイートしてくれて嬉しいし。
Take lots of pictures, and I'd be so happy if you tweet lots of memories with this hashtag.
ツイートして？
Tweet it?
レディ？
Ready?
どうするどうする？
What should we do?
え、ちょっと、あのさ、あのさっきのリハーサルでさ、やったやつちょっとやろうよ。
Oh, wait, let's do that pose we did in rehearsal earlier.
ちょっとみんな見てて。みんなウルトラニブ好きというか。
Everyone, look closely. Do you like the cool look?
そうだよね、ウルトラニブ。クールな、クールな、私とノエルでちょっと見てて。
Right, ultra cool. Check out the cool me and Noel.
ちょっとかっこよく、かっこよくうつして。
Strike a cool, cool pose.
かっこいいじゃん。やっぱ背中合わせって。
It's so cool, back-to-back poses.
神なんだよね。こうやって手をね、手を差し伸べる
It's divine. Like stretching out your hand like this...
手を差し伸べる感じ？
Reaching out your hand?
手震えてきた。
My hands are starting to shake.
筋肉の疲れが。ちょ、どう？
My muscles are so tired. How is it?
ノエルちゃんもちょっと沿って。あ、あい。
Noel-chan, lean back a bit more. Ah, yes.
もうちょっとそっ。
Lean back a little more.
うわ、撮れた撮れた？
Whoa, did we get it, did we get it?
撮れた？かっこよく撮れた？
Did we get it? Did it look cool?
あともう一個あったじゃん。もう一個、もう一個あって貰うよ。
There was another one, right? Let's have you do one more.
あ、そう。これね、あの、やっぱね、みんなうーんって、これライブをさ。
Ah, right. This one, like, everyone's like "Yeah," doing this live.
ちょっと待って、ノエルちゃんポーズの硬い。
Wait, Noel-chan, your pose is so stiff.
うお！なんか、あ、来てる？来てる？来てる？どうこれ、できてんの、みんな？できてんの？
Whoa! Wait, is it coming in? Is everyone getting it? Are you getting it?
やっと足が痛む。ちょっとアプ、アプ、引くな引くな。やめろやめろ。
My legs are hurting. Zoom in, zoom out! Stop, stop!
愛の丘ちょっと。
With the hill of love...
ウルフスデイヤーの、なんか闇みたいな。ちょっと見ちゃいけないもん。
It's like Wolf's Slayer's darkness. Something we shouldn't look at.
下の部分はね、ちょっと見せていけない部分だったね。いや、これなんかみんなにもコメントを。
The lower part... was something we shouldn't show. Well, let's ask everyone for comments too.
コメント、せっかくね。どんなポーズがいいか。
Let's get comments on what kind of pose would be good.
なんかノエルの見たいのとか教えて。
Tell us what kind of poses you want to see from Noel.
今草しか生えてないよ。草しか生えてない。
There's only grass growing right now. Just grass.
芝生がりやって。芝生がり。
Mowing the lawn. Mowing the lawn.
あ、芝生がり。
Ah, mowing the lawn.
ぺぺぺぺぺぺぺぺぺ、ルカーティスか。
Pepepepe... are you Curtis?
なんだって。芸能人に初めて。
What's that? First time for a celebrity.
ハイタッチ、ハイタッチ。ちょっとあの、バカ、カウントバグがあるかもしれない。
High touch, high touch. Wait, the count might be bugged.
えい！えい！えい！えい！えい！えい！がんばって！えい！えい！えい！
Yay! Yay! Yay! Do your best! Yay! Yay! Yay!
見えづるカメラが。
The camera is hard to see.
ま、でもね、ついてますから。気持ちはついてるから。
Well, but you know, we've got feelings attached to it.
あとは、あ、でもタイタ、あ、タイタニックか、タイタニック。
Next is, oh, Titanic, right, Titanic.
タイタニックやろう、タイタニック。
Let's do Titanic!
るーるー、るーるー。あ、私、あ、身長一緒なんだ、実は。
Lu-lu-lu-lu. Oh, wait, we're actually the same height.
見えなくなっちゃった。それこそコスプレイヤーのあれよ。
Now you can't see me. That's true cosplayer style.
頑張ってね。どう？どう？
Do your best. How is it? How is it?
タイタニック、沈没しちゃう。
Titanic is going to sink!
これ運営さんが頑張って、沈没しちゃう。
Management is trying hard, but it's sinking!
家の楽しい。
Home is fun.
家の、逆転。
Home reversal.
やるやる、はい。ちょっと足、足、これ。
Let's do it, yes. Wait, my legs...
足が。ぷるぷるぷる。
My legs are shaking.
誕生、誕生祭。
Birthday, birthday festival.
あとは、うん。
And then...
あとは、電車ごっこやる？
And then, should we do a train game?
電車ごっこ。先頭。はい。見えてて。
Train game. The lead. Yes. Let's show them.
プープープープープー。
Choo-choo-choo-choo!
どこにいる、どこにいる。
Where are you, where are you?
何がいいの？
What's good?
いや、でもさ、男女昨日ほら、オカコロでさ、ドライブ。
Well, but yesterday, you know, OkaKoro did a drive stream.
隠してたじゃん。団長さ、ほら
You were hiding it. Chanchou, look.
あの結構ね、あの某ゲームで運転うまいって言われてるから、助手席の手をはい。
Since you're supposedly good at driving in a certain game, I put my hand on the passenger seat, yeah.
運転する。
Driving.
の手を。
Your hand.
それ何してる時のやつ？
What were you doing at that time?
え今、あのアクセル全開？
Uh, right now, are you full throttle?
今日ちょっと。
Today, a little...
運転してる姿だそうです。お分かりいただけたでしょうか？
That's apparently what you look like driving. Did you understand?
いや、一緒にドライブしようね今度は。
No, let's go for a drive together next time.
私の運転しようか。
Shall I drive?
じゃあ団長助手席。何人引くでしょうか？
Then Chanchou in the passenger seat. How many people will you run over?
やだ怖い！
No way, that's scary!
誕生日に何言ってんだよ！平和に行きたいな。
What are you saying on your birthday! I want to go peacefully.
平和にね。
Peacefully, yeah.
あと何がある？
What else is there?
あそか観客席、みんなと取りたくない写真？
Oh right, audience seats, a photo you want to take with everyone?
撮りたい！撮りたい！撮りたい！
I want to take it! I want to take it! I want to take it!
すげえ！エルフの皆が
Awesome! All the elves...
ゲストだからね、団長は。さあさあさあみんな
You're a guest, Chanchou. Come on everyone,
手を繋ぎたい。あ手繋ぐ？手繋ぎたい。あや！えい！
I want to hold hands. Oh, hold hands? I want to hold hands. Yay! Eh!
みんな！アリーナ！イエーイ！２回好き！イエーイって、やったね！
Everyone! Arena! Yay! Twice as much love! Yay! We did it!
つけてくれてありがとうね！ありがとう！写真撮影ピースピース！ピースピース！
Thank you for putting it on! Thank you! Photo shoot peace peace! Peace peace!
私たちのセンスなさすぎてさ、あのリハーサルの時にさ、どんなポーズ取るって言ってさ、ずっとなんか
Our sense was so lacking, you know, during rehearsal, when we talked about what poses to do, the whole time...
カフェっていうかさ、ダブルピースするしかないやつ見てて、ちょ、ちょっとカメラさアップにしてこう、こう、こうでしょ、私たち。
We were just looking at things like cafe or double-peacing, wait, let's zoom the camera up, like this, like this, right?
イエーイ！いー！うわ！やめて！やめて！それやめて！
Yay! Ee! Woah! Stop it! Stop it! Stop that!
ちょっと痛い人みたいになっちゃったじゃん。一緒にハート写すのやめようね、なお。そうだよ、せっかく
It ended up looking like some painful person. Let's stop reflecting hearts together, Nao. That's right, after all that...
ねえ、従ってんのにね、ピース。ね。で、チューリングラブ。
Hey, even though we follow it, peace. Yeah. And Turing Love.
チュチュチュリーナ走ってっちゃう。でもこれね
Chu chu chu ring-a running off. But this, you know...
私たちさ、あの裏でさ練習してたじゃん。そしたらさ、サッソウと現れたさ、あのスタッフさんの方がうまかったの。
The two of us practiced behind the scenes, right? And then, staff-san who gallantly appeared was actually better at it.
なんかも「こうですよ」みたいな言うこともなく、なんか目の前でね、こうピンピンピンピンピンして、だからリズムに合わせでなんか
Without even saying "like this", right in front of us, they were like *ping ping ping*, so matching the rhythm...
チュルンナン、チュルンナン、ちょうど、ちょっと面目ないね、私たち。
Churun-nan, churun-nan, right, we look a bit shameful, don't we?
なんか、ねえ？出る？出る？あそこ。
Like, right? Will it come out? Will it come out? Over there.
あちらの代わりに。負けてらんねえおなって、ちょっとギリギリまで練習してた。
In place of that one. We couldn't afford to lose, so we practiced until the very last minute.
あ、私もついた。イエーイ、チュッチュッ。イエーイ、イエーイ、イエーイ。いい。
Ah, I got it too. Yay, chuchu. Yay, yay, yay. Good.
ちょっと、あ、あれしたい。何？
Wait, ah, I want to do that. What?
お米？違う！待って、ちょっと待って。はい、こい。え、これでも映るこれ。
Rice? No! Wait, hold on. Yes, come here. Eh, does this even show up?
ね、なんでさ大きいハートじゃなくて、ちっちゃい方を、あ、こうか、こうして、こうしよう、上か。
Hey, why not a big heart, but a small one, ah, like this, let's do this, the top?
髪の毛が、あ、めぐ、めぐってみたいになっちゃった。あ、扇風機が。
My hair became like Megu-megutte. Ah, the electric fan...
扇風機がバッチリ、のえちゃんはつまり電気の塊なんだね。
The fan is spot-on, so Noel-chan is basically a lump of electricity, huh.
いやそうかもしれない、団長。どういう、どういう風に、どういう風に、ちょっと適用できなかった。
Yeah, that might be it, Chanchou. How, how, in what way, I couldn't adapt.
ちょっと無茶ぶりが過ぎたらしい。え、他は？みんなクサクサとかテーテーとか言ってる。
It seems the unreasonable demand was too much. Eh, what about others? Everyone is saying "kusakusa" or "teete".
なんかある？「さとてて」は一緒じゃなくね？なんか、ほんと、私たちアイドルなのにアイドルポーズが分からないんだよね。
Anything else? "Sa tote te" isn't together, right? Like, really, we're idols, but we don't know idol poses.
はが、じゃあ待って、のえちゃんのおもうさ、え、これがのえちゃんのおもう？あ、でもなんかちゃんとハグできたね。ねえ。
Ha, then wait, what Noel-chan thinks, eh, is this what Noel-chan thinks? Ah, but it looks like we managed to hug properly. Yeah.
いつもさ、なんかうまくいかなくてさ、ハグ練習してさ、私のお、お、女です。
Always, somehow it didn't go well, practicing hugs, my, o, womanly...
うちの、うちの、えー、なんて、男性、男性、え、ちょっとね、みんなには見えないけど、ここにも指輪が。あ、そう今日ね、つけてる。
Our, our, um, what, male, male, um, wait, though it's not visible to everyone, there's a ring here too. Ah, that's right, today I'm wearing it.
ちょっと手袋で見えないけどね。そう手袋で見えないけど、ちゃんとね内側に、本当だもん、本当だもん、本当だもん、２人でつけてる。
You can't see it because of the gloves. Yeah, you can't see it with the gloves, but right on the inside, it's true, it's true, it's true, the two of us are wearing it.
つけてるんだ。そう、つけてるし。あ、出れてる。
We're wearing it. Yeah, we're wearing it. Ah, it's showing.
でもね、指輪はあんまり見せびらかすものじゃないんだよ。まあ、たしかにね、これはね。もっとひっそりと輝かせるものだから。
But you know, rings aren't really something to show off. Well, that's true, this one. It's something to make shine quietly.
そうだね。みて！自慢してんじゃん。のえちゃん、のえちゃんとさ、久しぶりじゃない？
That's right. Look! You're showing off! Noel-chan, isn't it been a while since you and Noel-chan...
そうなんだ、久しぶり。そうだからね、お久しぶり。なんかうん、そりゃそうだよね。
That's right, it's been a while. So that's why, long time no see. Yeah, well, of course.
いや、違うね。そんなことないよ。いやなんかやっぱね、やっててそんな、いきなり、そんな日曜日配信になに、のえ、のえちゃん、なんですか？
No, that's wrong. It's not like that. No, like, doing it so suddenly, Sunday distribution, what, Noe-chan, what is it?
うちは、やっぱほらね、やっぱ、ほら、あのね、フレアにもこれ交流関係っていうのがるからやっぱ妻として、そういうのをこうやって見守るっていう係が。
For us, y'know, look, y'know, Flare also has these relations, so as a wife, there's a role to watch over those things.
私知ってるよ。のえちゃんが配信でね、なんか「いや、団長フレアを誘うんだ」って
I know. Noel-chan on stream said, "No, I'm going to invite Flare,"
フレアが言うけどさ、誘う、誘う？
Flare says that, but invite, invite?
なんか、のえちゃんね、なんかあの、ハグちゃんまとね、似てる所があって。
Like, Noel-chan has some similarities with Hug-chan...
あ、で、まさかのハプニング
Ah, and then, an unexpected happening—
なんかね
you know,
あの、そう、やろうよ！みたいなのね、そう一瞬声かかるんだけど、いつにする？が進まないやつ
like, "Let's do it!" we'd bring it up for a second, but it never gets past "When should we?"
でなんか
And like,
いや今日会うから今日、ほら、こんな服似合う、こんな服似合うって。
"Well, since we're meeting today, like, 'Look, this outfit suits you, this outfit suits you!'"
でも、そう、でも今日はね、なんかがひでも来るからって
"Even if come hell or high water, I'll be there today,"
ノエルちゃんが言ってくれて
Noel-chan said.
そう、絶対行くぜって言って
Yeah, she said, "I'm definitely going!"
そう、なんかノエルちゃん、ちょっとさ、先日体調ちょっと頑張りすぎちゃって、腰痛めっ…腰がね、ちょっと
Yeah, Noel-chan, um, recently pushed herself a bit too hard with her health and hurt her back... her back was a bit...
でもあり、もう治ったからぴょんぴょん離れ…そう、大丈夫？って聞いたらね
But she's already better now, bouncing around... yeah, when I asked, "Are you okay?"
絶対行くからっ！
"I'm definitely going!"
そう、上手上手。来ました。そう、ありがとう。
(Laughs) Smooth, smooth. She came. Yeah, thank you.
いや、本当にちょっとお山させていただいて、ありがとうございます。こうやってね、素敵な
Yeah, thank you so much for participating. Thank you so much for such a wonderful...
いや、正直2曲、2曲がすごく良かったから、本当3曲目に、あのチュチュチュリングラブ本当にいいのかなって思いながらも
Honestly, the first two songs were so great that for the third song, I was wondering, "Is Chuchuchuring Love really okay?" while thinking that,
でもね、私、あのノエルちゃんと練習とかでさ、あの歌ってさ
but still, Noel-chan and I, during practice and stuff, when we sang...
なんかあんまりうまく取れ、なんか歌えないよって言ってさ、とりあえず1回試しにさ、自分の歌がどれぐらい下手なのかっていうのを、試す録音したの。
we'd be like, "We can't sing this well!" and at least once, just to test how bad our singing was, we recorded a test.
なにそれ！どういうこと？そう、で、なんか聞いて、あ、なんか
"What's that?! What do you mean?" Yeah. And then we listened to it and went, "Ah, like..."
頑張らなきゃ！って
"We gotta work harder!"
いや、でも、男子ね、最初、早口、ね、どうしても言えなかったんだけど、でもまあまあ言えたから
But man, at first, with the fast-paced lyrics, I couldn't say it no matter what, but since I managed to say it okay more or less,
いいじゃないかなと。練習の成果あったね。成果あった！マジで。最初やばかったからね。
I think it was good. Practice paid off. It paid off! Seriously. Because at first it was terrible.
ちょっともうダメかもしれないって言って、言ってたもん。待ってた。うんうん。
We were saying, "This might be no good anymore." We were waiting. Yeah, yeah.
え、で、なんか、スタッフさんがね、もう、もうそろそろおひらきにしてくださいって
And then, like, the staff told us, "Please wrap things up soon."
え、そう、おひらきって、え、これから焼肉ってこと？
"Eh? Wrap things up? Does that mean yakiniku from here on?"
え、今、ありがとうございました！えちゅっ！えっ！
"Eh, thank you very much for now! Echu! Eh?!"
え、ね、ね、2曲歌うの？次も。
"Eh, hey, hey, are we singing two songs? Next too?"
よし、頑張ろう！と思って。ちょっと次の曲は、ノエルちゃんいると地獄になっちゃう
"Alright, let's do our best!" I thought. But if Noel-chan is in the next song, it's gonna turn into hell—
あ、あ、分かりました。あ、帰れってことね。あ、分かりました。
"Ah, ah, I see. Ah, you mean go home? Ah, I see."
ノエルちゃん、サンズと喧嘩しないでね。
"Noel-chan, don't fight with Sun Tzu, okay?"
サンズのぬいぐるみ、いるんだよね、そう。いるんだよ。じゃ、仲良く見てるね、サンズと。じゃあ、頑張ってね。お邪魔しました、みんな。ありがとう。じゃあね。
"There's a Sun Tzu plushie, right? Yeah, it's there. Well, watch over each other nicely with Sun Tzu. Alright, do your best. Thanks for having us, everyone. Thank you. Bye-bye."
見守っててね、一緒に。
"Watch over us together."
はい、ということでですね、ちょっと一生水を飲んでいいですか？
"Alright, so um, can I drink water for a moment?"
あれ、お水どこ？お水どこ？あ、金づば帰ってきた。
"Wait, where's my water? Where's my water? Ah, Kinzuba came back."
ちょっとね、ノエルちゃんを帰してしまったんですけど、帰したことにはちょっと理由がありまして
"I sent Noel-chan home, but there's a bit of a reason for that—"
あの、次の曲なんですけど、あの、次の曲はですね、ちょっとヒントをみんなに出したいと思う。
"Um, for the next song, um, for the next song, I'd like to give everyone a hint."
最近10周年を迎えた作品って何ですか？
"What work recently celebrated its 10th anniversary?"
知ってる人いるかな？
"I wonder if anyone knows?"
若干のコメントジサがある。
"There's a slight comment delay."
最近10周年を迎えた作品があります。
"There is a work that recently celebrated its 10th anniversary."
あるね、コメントね。
"It's there, comments, yeah."
はい、えー、まあコメント当たりがいますね。
"Yes, um, well, there are some correct comments."
ではですね、えっと、今回ですね、つい最近新曲も出ました。えー、カゲロウプロジェクトから、ちょっと私1曲歌わせていただきたいなと思います。聞いてください、「RED」。
"So, um, this time, a brand new song was just recently released. Um, from Kagerou Project, I'd like to sing a song. Please listen to 'RED'."
だんだん目が回って 夕焼けが燦々空に散っていった
My head is spinning around, as the sunset scatters dazzlingly across the sky.
滲み出す雲に 言葉が出なくなるのは何故？
Why is it that words fail me before these bleeding clouds?
遠回りの近道と 朽ち果てた線路
A shortcut that's a detour, and rusted railroad tracks.
湿った手を掴んだまま 速足で進む
Walking briskly while holding damp hands.
互い違いの畦道が 水みたいに揺らいで
Staggered footpath ridges wavering like water,
蝉の音を暈したまま 立ち尽くしていた
standing completely still with the cicadas' hum blurred.
夏が昨日を通り越して行く
Summer passes right over yesterday.
草の匂い 俄雨の温度 混ざり合ったら
When the scent of grass and the warmth of a sudden shower mix,
僕らが今まで知らない日々は
the days we've never known until now
数え切れない積乱雲の奥で 確実に呼んでいる
are surely calling out from deep within countless cumulonimbus clouds.
泥にまみれた 僕の手を拒むように
As if rejecting my mud-stained hands,
難しいって恥ずかしんだ 君と僕じゃ違うから
you felt shy, saying "It's difficult," because you and I are different.
だんだん目が回って 夕暮れが燦々空に散っていった
My head is spinning around, as dusk scatters dazzlingly across the sky.
思い出すほどに 言葉が出なくなるのは何故？
Why is it that the more I remember, the less words come out?
道連れに賛成なら笑って とっくに遠く離れた
If you agree to be my companion, smile. Long since far away,
どこまでも続く空は知っているの
Does the sky that stretches on forever know?
心はいつまで君を覚えていられるのだろう
How long can my heart continue to remember you?
ゴールを目指しているようで
It seems like I am aiming for a goal,
本当は終わりなし永遠を求めているの
But in truth, I am seeking an endless eternity.
この広い世界で この小さな体で
In this vast world, with this tiny body,
まだ何か伝えられるはず
Surely there is still something I can convey.
限りなく伸ばした この指の向こうで
Beyond these fingers stretched out infinitely,
私を照らす一番星 君のように
Shines the morning star that illuminates me, just like you.
道に咲く花が風に踊るように
Like a flower blooming by the path dancing in the wind,
心は今でも揺らぎ 君の面影浮かべる
My heart still wavers, bringing up your image.
形あるものは消えていく
Things with form eventually fade away,
だけど読みたくない 人の夢「儚」と
Yet I don't want to read people's dreams as "ephemeral."
この暗い世界で この冷たい人波で
In this dark world, in this cold crowd of people,
まだ何か見つけられるはず
Surely I can still find something.
背伸びしてばかりじゃ 気付けない足元で
Right at my feet, which I wouldn't notice if I only stand on tiptoe,
私を包む焚火花 君のように
Are the bonfire flowers embracing me, just like you.
命あるもの全て輝く
Everything with life shines.
命あるもの全て苦しむ
Everything with life suffers.
雨が降り又晴れる空のように 繰り返すんだろう
Like the sky that clears up after the rain, it must repeat over and over.
この広い世界で この小さな体で
In this vast world, with this tiny body,
まだ何か伝えられるはず
Surely there is still something I can convey.
限りなく伸ばした この指の向こうで
Beyond these fingers stretched out infinitely,
私を照らす一番星 輝く
Shines the morning star that illuminates me.
この暗い世界で 君のいない世界でも
In this dark world, even in a world without you,
まだ何か見つけられるはず
Surely I can still find something.
小さい愛のカケラを 温もり感じたり
Feeling the warmth of small fragments of love,
私を照らす一番星のように優しく 強く生きてきてくれた 君のように
Just like the morning star that illuminates me, living gently and strongly, just like you.
あー、ちょっと過酷すぎる...
Ah, man... That's way too harsh.
はい、本日、えー、最初で最後の、
Right, today, um, the first and last
かっこいい曲が終わりました。
cool song has just finished.
いかがだったでしょうか? いや、今回ね、
How was it? Man, this time, y'know,
いや、この曲もね、あの、Suara-patraが作ってくれた、
this song too, uh, Suara-patra made it,
ていうか、演奏ね、してくれたんですけど、
or rather, performed it, y'know,
そう、めちゃくちゃかっこいいんですよ。曲がすごくかっこよくて、
Yeah, it's super cool. The song is super cool,
で、あの、この曲どうしても、かっこよく聴かせたかったので、
and, uh, since I really wanted to make this song sound cool,
ちょっとコーラスだけ事前に、ちょっと撮らせていただいたんですけど、
I had them record just the chorus beforehand, but
どうだったみんな? ちょっともう、コーラスめちゃくちゃ難しかった。
how was it everyone? Man, the chorus was super hard.
でも、コーラスが死なないように歌うのも難しかった!
And singing it so the chorus doesn't get drowned out was hard!
どう? 初めて聴いたって人めるかもしれない。
How is it? Some might be hearing it for the first time.
これあの、カゲロウプロジェクトさんの曲なんだけどね、
This is, y'know, Kagerou Project's song,
ぜひぜひ、あの、元の曲も聴いてほしいなっていう、あの
so I really want you to listen to the original song too, y'know,
はい、かっこいい曲、最後だった?
Yeah, was that the last cool song?
よかった! 最高だった! ありがとう!
Great! It was the best! Thank you!
え、でですね、あの、今回、あの、ご用意させていただいた曲っていうのは、
Um, and so, uh, this time, uh, the song we prepared for you
あの、実は、次で、最後なんですよ。
is actually the last one next.
次で、もう最後なんですよ。早いね、あっというま。
The next one is already the last. That's fast, time flies.
なんですけど、あの、まあね、ちょっとまだ帰らないで。
That being said, um, well, y'know, don't leave just yet.
ちょっとまだ、もしかしたら、サプライズでなんかあるかも、
There might be a surprise or something...
自分て言ったらサプライズじゃねえわ。
If I say it myself, it's not a surprise.
でも、でも、でも最後まで聴いててほしいなって思います。
But, but, I want you to listen all the way to the end.
ま、ちょっと最後、こっちの今回の曲はね、あの、最後の曲、えー、
Well, finally, for this song, uh, the last song, um,
誕生日に歌いたい曲だったので、ちょっと聴いててもらえますか?
it was a song I wanted to sing on my birthday, so please listen to it.
私本当はなんか歌いたい曲だったんですけど
I actually wanted to sing a different song, but
ちょっと歌わせていただいても 自分 歌わせていただいてもいいすか！？
is it okay if I... if I sing it anyway?!
ツイッターよろしくね？
Check out my Twitter, okay?
ってことでですね、では歌わせていただきたいと思います。
So with that said, I'd like to perform it for you.
えー ウィンドクライミング 風にそよがれて
Um, 'Wind Climbing ~Kaze ni Soyogarete~'.
誕生日のたびに
Every time a birthday comes around,
何を祝うのかがずっと謎だった
I've always wondered what we were celebrating.
見えなくなってしまったものは
When I learned that things once lost
二度とかえないと知ったとき
can never be recovered,
年を取ることに後悔と一日が過ぎていく恐怖を感じた
I felt regret for aging and fear as each day slipped away.
どうにもならない今日だけれど
Today is just how it is, but
平坦な道じゃきっとつまらない
a flat path would surely be boring.
きみと生きていく明日だから
Since tomorrow is built on living with you,
振り仰ぐくらいでちょうどいい
looking up just a bit is right where I want to be.
脇道を独り歩く そんな自分にみとれてみたり
Admiring myself as I walked down a side path alone,
歩き疲れたあの人へ 冷たい言葉を平気で放つ
and casually tossing cold words at someone tired from walking.
調子づいていた小さな自分
My puffed-up, little self
風にあそばれて やっとここに立っていた
was finally playing in the wind, standing right here.
どうにもならない今日だけれど
Today is just how it is, but
平坦な道じゃきっとつまらない
a flat path would surely be boring.
きみと生きていく明日だから
Since tomorrow is built on living with you,
振り仰ぐくらいでちょうどいい
looking up just a bit is right where I want to be.
どうにもならない今日だけれど
Today is just how it is, but
平坦な道じゃきっとつまらない
a flat path would surely be boring.
きみと生きていく明日だから
Since tomorrow is built on living with you,
振り仰ぐくらいでちょうどいい
looking up just a bit is right where I want to be.
今日はみんな会いに来てくれてどうもありがとうございます！
Thank you so much everyone for coming to see me today!
誕生日を盛り上げるために、みんなも一緒に最後まで盛り上がってくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if everyone could get hyped and hype me up all the way to the end to celebrate my birthday!
手拍子！
Clap your hands!
転んでできた傷の痛みに
If I searched for something to match
見合う何かを求めたなら幻
the pain of wounds from falling, it was just an illusion.
どうにもならない今日はせめて 笑い話にかえられますように
May today, however it goes, at least turn into a funny story.
どうにもならない今日はせめて
May today, however it goes, at least
笑い話にかえられますように
turn into a funny story.
きみと生きていく明日だから
Since tomorrow is built on living with you,
振り仰ぐくらいでちょうどいい
looking up just a bit is right where I want to be.
どうにもならない今日だけれど
Today is just how it is, but
平坦な道じゃきっとつまらない
a flat path would surely be boring.
きみと生きていく明日だから
Since tomorrow is built on living with you,
振り仰ぐくらいでちょうどいい
looking up just a bit is right where I want to be.
はあ... やっぱ歌うときにさ... はあって言ってるのをさ、あんまり出したくないなと思ってさ
Haah... You know, when I sing, I feel like I don't want people to hear me going 'haah...' like that.
皆さんありがとうございます。あの... 思って頑張るんだけどさ、終わった瞬間にどっと...
Thank you everyone. Um... I try my best, but the moment it ends, it hits me all at once...
来ちゃってさ。ちょっとお水飲みますね。
I'm gonna drink some water.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
で、この曲、やっぱりちょっと何ていうか、こう
And this song, you know, sort of...
エルフレのみんなもすごくお世話になってて
Elfriends, everyone has been so supportive,
なんかこの歌詞すごく刺さるなって思ってたから
and I thought, "This song really hits home."
誕生日には絶対歌いたいなって思ってたので、
So I was hoping to definitely sing it for my birthday,
本当にその曲歌わせていただいて本当にありがとうございました。
so truly, thank you so much for letting me sing this song.
そして、あの、ま、今日ね私を初めて知ってくれた人も
And, well, for those of you getting to know me for the first time today,
結構この曲初めて聴いた人もいい曲だと思ってくれたんじゃないかなと思うし、
I hope you thought this was a great song, even if it was your first time hearing it.
ね、あの知ってる人もね、知ってる人はなんか懐かしいなって気持ちに浸ってくれたかなって
And for those who already know it, I hope it brought back some nostalgic feelings.
思ったりします。本当に、本当にみんな今日遊びに来てくれてありがとうね。
Truly, thank you all so much for coming to hang out with me today.
きたからってだけでも十分嬉しいんですけど、
I'm just so happy that you came!
はい。
Yes.
あ、なんか待って。ん?
Oh, wait, what?
なんか今運営さんからプレゼントがあるって聴いたんだけど、
I heard there's a present from the management,
ちょっと行ってみてもいい?ちょっと待ってて。
can I go check it out? Hang on a second.
なんだ?
What is it?
なんや、なんや。
What, what, what?
なんじゃおらあ!
What the heck?!
なんや?
What's this?
ねこやき、にゃーん!
Meow-yo, meow-nyan!
え、これ何?あの、ウェルカム2000って伏線だったの?
Wait, what? Is this like a Welcome 2000... is that a hint?
にゃんにゃん、にゃんにゃんにゃん!
Nyan nyan nyan nyan!
え、これ運営さんがプレゼントしてくれたの?
Wait, did management give this to me as a present?
なんか髪の毛もね、かわいい、かわいいからって、うわあ!
And my hair looks so cute! I'm crying!
え、ちょっと待ってよ。そういうサプライズはさ、嬉しくって泣いちゃうじゃん。
Wait, wait, getting a surprise like this just makes you want to cry, right?
ねえ、なんかみんなからもいっぱいプレゼントをもらって、運営さんからもプレゼントをもらって、え、しかもこれってさ、運営さんだけじゃないよね。どう考えてもパパも関わってるよね?
You know, I got so many presents from everyone, and from management too... and wait, this is from management, but honestly, Papa was involved too, right?
え、パパありがとう!エルフの耳もよく描いてると。
Papa, thank you! Elfried's ears are drawn so well too!
え、でと、あのなんかあれなの。最近ホロライブがさ、なんかあの猫耳流行ってるみたいなさ、ギョフこれ運営さんの趣味なの?
And you know, lately Hololive has been all about cat ears... is this a management hobby?
なんか趣味っぽい。上の趣味だそうです。きゅ、ピンじゃないんだよ。
Seems like an Ue-san hobby. It's not a pin!
あのね、ちょっとこのね、あの髪型とか、あの猫耳とかは、ちょっと後日、あの配信で、別の配信の時に、あのみんなに見せたいなって思います。本当にありがとうございます。素敵なプレゼントありがとう!
Anyway, I'll show off this hairstyle and cat ears in a separate stream later! Thank you so much for the wonderful presents!
じゃあちょっと、いったみんなのところに帰るね。
Let's head back to everyone's place for a bit.
えいっ。
Alright.
えー、嬉しい!
Yay!
ありがとうございます。本当に、本当にみんなもありがとう。運営さんも本当にありがとう、今日歌う、歌うことができたのも運営さんのおかげで本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much, really, everyone! And management too, thank you for letting me sing today. I'm truly grateful!
でですね、今回私からの、あの、みんなにね、あの、告知があります。
And so, I have an announcement for everyone today.
みんなにプレゼント、プレゼントって言うとなんか金取るんかいっつって。
I'm giving everyone a present—well, saying "present" sounds like I'm giving out money or something!
でも、ちょっと一生懸命みんなに喜んでもらえるものとか考えたから、ちょっと見てくれないかな?
But I really worked hard to think of something that would make everyone happy, so I hope you'll take a look.
ちょっと、どどん!
Ta-da!
こちら!
Here it is!
不知火フレア誕生日記念2021、ボイス&グッズ全部セット!
Shiranui Flare Birthday Celebration 2021 Voice & Goods Complete Set!
はーい!
Ta-da!
こちら、ご用意させていただきました!パパがね、忙しい合間を縫って、私を可愛くお仕立てしていただいて、可愛い衣装で、今回描き下ろしていただきました!パパもありがとう、運営様ありがとうございます!
This is something we've prepared for you, and Papa worked hard on his days off to dress me up so cute in this wonderful outfit, which he drew for this occasion! Thank you, Papa, thank you management!
で、グッズの気になるグッズの中身もちょっと見ていきましょう。お願いします。
And let's take a look at the contents of the goods you're curious about, shall we? Please!
こちら、え、ブック型ケース。
First is the Book-Type Case.
ちょっとね、私がいね、今回、あの、なんかコンセプトを決めたくて、あの、なんか絵本みたいなコンセプトにしたくて、なのは、あのこういう本の形をした、あの、箱。だから、なんかあの領収書入れるとか、小物入れるとか、
I wanted to make a concept for this time, like a picture book, so I made a box shaped like a book where you can put receipts or accessories.
なんかそういうことができる箱になってます。あるだけでも、ちょっと可愛いんじゃないかなって思ってみました。用意してみましたが、いかがでしょうか?
Something like that—I thought it'd be cute just to have it around, so I prepared one, how do you like it?
これだけじゃないのよ。もう回。どどん!
That's not all, though! Next, ta-da!
こちら、え、ブックカバーと、え、木製のしおりが付いております。
This is the Book Cover and Wooden Bookmark!
こちら、本のタイトルがね、
And the book title is...
Wonderful Life.
素晴らしい人生なのとさ、私の人生とても素晴らしい人生でしということで、え、こちらのタイトル付いております。
"A wonderful life is a wonderful life," so that's why this title is included!
はい、こちらもセットで付いております。木製のしおりも一緒に使ってね。
Yes, this also comes as a set, so please use the wooden bookmark together!
はい、まだありますよ。どどん!
Alright, there's more! Ta-da!
これいら
This is...
え、これ、お、え、きんつばこれいる？
Huh? Is Kintsuba here?
すげえ視聴者数
Look at that crazy viewer count!
ね、待って、すごいしょ。私よりも目立つんじゃね？
Wait, isn't that amazing? He's standing out more than me!
ちょっと、ちょっと？
Wait a minute...
ま、でもですね、あの、つくーさんからね、あの、
But you know, Tsukumo-san made...
私のぬいぐるみ作っていただいたので
a plushie of me,
一緒にね、あったらいいんじゃないかなって 前にね、ちょっとあの、エルフラにはね、
so I thought it'd be nice to have it here together. Earlier, I was telling Elfrein...
あの、持ってるといいんじゃない？みたいなの、ちょっと話ををしてたんですけど、ま、今回こちらきんつばのぬいぐるみがつきます！
how it might be nice to have one, but this time, Kintsuba's plushie is included!
はーい！よかったね、きんつばおじさん。
Yay! Good for you, Uncle Kintsuba.
なんのSEだろ。
What was that sound effect?
はい。でですね、今回このセット、基本的にはグッズこのセットになってるんですけど、今回ちょっと頑張らせていただきました。
Right. And for this set, normally it comes with this merchandise, but we worked really hard on it this time.
はい、どどん！
Tada!
はい、今回特典ボイスついておりまして、で、え、直筆サイン入り、え、ま、これは数量限定になってしまうんですけど
Yes, it comes with bonus voice packs, and a handwritten signature version—though this will be in limited quantities—
はい、今回はですね、あの、サイン書かせていただきたいなって思っております。
we really wanted to sign them ourselves this time.
ただ、あの、出た瞬間すぐになくなるみたいなのね、そういうふうにはちょっとなりのはちょっとあれな、なれかなと思って、あの、いつも、あの、ま、ちょっと売り切れそうなやつの
However, since they usually sell out the very second they go on sale, we wanted to avoid that if possible, so for items that usually sell out fast...
あの、枚数の倍用意してるので
we prepared double the usual number,
すぐはたぶん売り切れないんじゃないかなと、はい、思っています。
so I think they won't sell out instantly this time.
ちょっと一生懸命サイン書きますので、ぜひぜひ買って下さい。
I'll write the signatures with all my heart, so please be sure to grab one!
ボイスの方はですね、あの、5個ついております。
As for the voice clips, there are 5 of them included.
なんかね、あの、ちょっとガチ恋向けがちょっと多くなっちゃった
Somehow, there ended up being quite a few for hardcore fans...
でですね、あの、なんかホムラくんが、あの、いい子にしたらいいことあるかもね、って
And you know, Homura-kun kept saying, "If you're a good boy, something good might happen,"
って言ってた、けど、なんかいいことあるのかもしれないね、ってことでホムラボイス付いてるみたいですょ。
so it seems there's a Homura voice included with that idea in mind.
はい、ということで、え、こちらグッズの紹介でしたー！
So, that concludes the merchandise introduction!
はい、あの今概要欄にですね、ブースのURL追加されましたので、こちらも、え、確認してみてください！
Also, the Booth URL has been added to the description, so please check that out as well!
はい、まだね、なんがあるんですよね。実は、あの、ちょっとなんか、もしオリジナルソングを作るんだったら、なんかく、どどどどんどこどことか
Right, there's still more. Actually, we were talking before about how if we were to make an original song, we'd want something with a fun beat...
みたいなのね、そういうのを作りたいよね、みたいな話ををしてたんですけど、はい、あの、こちら、ご用意いたしました。どどん！
like "dododon dokodoko," and well... we've prepared just that! Tada!
違うんかい！君とぼく、だ、君とつむぐストーリーじゃないんかい！
Wait, that's wrong! It's "You and Me"—wait, isn't it "A Story We Weave Together with You"?!
はい、今回ですね、えー、ちょっと忙しい中運営さんとか、あの、関わってくださった作曲者さんとか、えー、本当に本当にあのSEさんとか動画師さんとか、えーロゴとか作ってくださったグラフィッカーさんとか本当に本当に皆さんありがとうございました。
And this time, I want to thank everyone so much: the management who worked hard despite their busy schedules, the composers who helped out, the sound engineers, video editors, and the graphic artists who made the logos. Thank you all so much!
えーこちら楽曲がですね、iTunesストアで、え、0時から、え、フルで、え、販売が開始されるんですけれども
As for this song, it will go on sale in full starting at midnight on the iTunes Store.
どんな曲かやっぱ聴かないと買えねぇよなっておもいますよね。
But you probably think, "I can't buy it without listening to what kind of song it is first," right?
なので、ちょっとみんなね、あの、今回初出しになります、こちらの曲、ちょっと聴いて、え、最後終わりたいなって、思っております。
So, since this is the very first time we're premiering it, I want everyone to listen to this song and finish off with it.
こちらの曲一体どんな曲なんでしょうかっていうね。はい、ぜひぜひ聴いていただきたいです。
I hope you'll all give it a listen to find out what kind of song it is!
ではですね、ちょと最後これでこのまま終わっちゃうんですけど、あの、挨拶は無いからね、本当にもうここで最後歌い終わったらもう終わりだからみんな本当に来てくれてありがとうございます。
Well then, we'll be ending right after this, so there won't be any closing remarks afterwards. Once I finish singing here, that's it! Thank you all so much for coming.
改めてみんなにちゃんと御礼をさせてください。スーパーチャットも本当にみなさんありがとうございます。
Let me express my gratitude to you all once again. Thank you all so much for the Super Chats as well.
遊びに来てくださった方も本当にありがとうございます。よかったら、チャンネル登録とか、高評価とかしてくれたら嬉しいです。ツイッターのフォローとかもしてくれたら嬉しいです。サブスクライブトゥーザチャンネル
Thank you so much to everyone who came to hang out. If you'd like, I'd be happy if you could subscribe to the channel, leave a like, or follow me on Twitter. Subscribe to the channel!
ていうことで、最後みんなのTwitter、声は忘れないでお願いしますね。
With that said, don't forget to tweet about it!
てことで、最後盛り上がって行きがー！スマイルアンドゴー！
And with that, let's get hyped right to the end! Smile & Go!!
こんぬいー！準備はいいかー 今日はみんなで騒ぎましょう！！
Konnui! Are you ready? Today let's make some noise together!!
せーの！はい！はい！はい！……
Ready, set! Hey! Hey! Hey!......
やってきましたみんなに会える時間です
The time to meet everyone has finally come.
歌とかゲームとか見てほしくて（耐久配信ごめんなさい）
I wanted you to see me sing and play games (sorry for the endurance stream).
あっという間に過ぎてしまう毎日に
In these days that pass by in the blink of an eye,
乗り遅れないように手をつなごう（もうちょっとだけ一緒にいよう）
Let's hold hands so we don't fall behind (let's stay together just a little longer).
こんぬー！ 準備はいいーっ！
Konnuu! Are you ready?!
今日はみんなで騒ぎましょう！
Let's all make some noise today!
せーのっ！
Ready, go!
はい！
Yeah!
気づけば隣にいてくれてありがとう
Before I knew it, you were by my side, thank you.
どんな高い壁だって
No matter how high the wall,
（ハイハイ！）
(Hai, hai!)
ひと飛びで飛び越えて
leaping over it in a single bound,
（ハイハイ！）
(Hai, hai!)
誰も見たことない世界に みんなで行こうよ！
let's all go to a world no one has ever seen!
君とSmile & Go!! 楽しんだもん勝ち
You and Smile & Go!! Whoever has fun wins!
君とSmile & Go!! ハジけたもん勝ち
You and Smile & Go!! Whoever breaks loose wins!
ここに笑顔で集まれば 最高でしょ (yeah!!)
If we gather here with smiles, it'll be the best, right? (Yeah!!)
僕らSmile & Go!! いつも全力で
We're Smile & Go!! Always giving our all,
僕らSmile & Go!! 遊びまくろう
we're Smile & Go!! Playing to our heart's content!
だって (そうさ) この日常が大切な宝物だよ Smile & Go!!
Because (that's right) this everyday life is a precious treasure, Smile & Go!!
雑談配信今日は
Today's chatting stream
まったり行きましょう
let's take it easy.
たわいない話聞いて欲しくて （聞いて聞いてちょっと聞いてよ～）
I want you to listen to my idle talk (Listen, listen, listen to me for a bit~)
たまにはお休みしようと思ったけれど やっぱり晩酌配信しちゃおうかな
I thought about taking a break for once, but maybe I'll do a evening drink stream after all
（用意ができたら乾杯！）
(Once preparations are ready, cheers!)
ありふれたこの時も一緒に過ごしたら
If we spend these mundane moments together,
いつの間にかキラキラと
before we know it, they sparkle
（ハイハイ！）
(Hai, hai!)
何よりも輝いて
shining brighter than anything else
（ハイハイ！）
(Hai, hai!)
言葉には出来ない想いが溢れ出しちゃうよ
Feelings that words can't express overflow!
君とLet's Enjoy!! 歌ってみようよ
You and Let's Enjoy!! Let's try singing together!
君とLet's Enjoy!! 心を一つに
You and Let's Enjoy!! With our hearts as one,
どこにいたって優しさは届いてるよ (yeah!!)
no matter where you are, my kindness reaches you (yeah!!)
僕らLet's Enjoy!! テンション上げてさ
We're Let's Enjoy!! Raising our tension,
僕らLet's Enjoy!! はしゃぎまくろう
we're Let's Enjoy!! Let's party hard!
きっと (そうさ) 明日はもっと楽しいこと待っているから
Surely (that's right) tomorrow even more fun things are waiting for us!
レディースアンジェントルメン！
Ladies and gentlemen!
よそ見してたら置いてっちゃうから 最後まで盛り上がってこ！
If you look away, I'll leave you behind, so get hyped till the very end!
君の街お邪魔して よく聞いて
Visiting your town, listen closely—
とんでも楽しい賢いしてけ… なんちゃって！
have some insanely fun time... Just kidding!
せーの ステージをGO！
Ready, Stage GO!
ずーっと見ていて私のことを これから先も期待してね？
Keep watching me always, and look forward to the future too?
予想不可能なワクワクをキミに送るから
Because I'll send unpredictable excitement straight to you!
君とSmile & Go!! 楽しんだもん勝ち
You and Smile & Go!! Whoever has fun wins!
君とSmile & Go!! ハジけたもん勝ち
You and Smile & Go!! Whoever breaks loose wins!
ここに笑顔で集まれば 最高でしょ (yeah!!)
If we gather here with smiles, it'll be the best, right? (Yeah!!)
僕らSmile & Go!! いつも全力で
We're Smile & Go!! Always giving our all,
僕らSmile & Go!! 遊びまくろう
we're Smile & Go!! Playing to our heart's content!
だって (そうさ) この日常が大切な宝物だよ Smile & Go!!
Because (that's right) this everyday life is a precious treasure, Smile & Go!!
とびきりの笑顔でいこう Smile & Go!!
Let's go with the brightest smiles, Smile & Go!!
君とSmile & Go!! 楽しんだもん勝ち
You and Smile & Go!! Whoever has fun wins!
よりのステージライブ聞いてくれてどうもありがとうございまーす！
Thank you so much for listening to my stage live!